{
    "id": "d31a00ec73a64bd4a5af8a3bf00da867",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If you had practiced every day, you …………………………",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will win",
                "will have won",
                "would have won"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had …………………………. I could buy a car.",
            "description": "When enough is used as an adjective it goes before the noun it modifies.",
            "answers": [
                "enough money",
                "money enough",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He was …………………………… to lend me 100 dollars.",
            "description": "When enough is used as an adverb, it goes after the adjective or adverb modified by it.",
            "answers": [
                "generous enough",
                "enough generous",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Don’t come tomorrow. I would rather you ………………………….. on Sunday.",
            "description": "After would rather we use a past tense with a present or future meaning.",
            "answers": [
                "come",
                "will come",
                "had come",
                "came"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Nothing happened, …………………………..?",
            "description": "In question tags, we use it to refer to nothing.",
            "answers": [
                "did they",
                "did that",
                "did it"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………… the film, I don’t want to read the book.",
            "description": "When we separate the clauses we get: I have seen the film. I don’t want to read the book.\r\nWe can combine them using having seen.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "Seen",
                "Seeing",
                "Having seen"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Everything is all right, …………………………?",
            "description": "In question tags we use it to refer to everything.",
            "answers": [
                "is it",
                "is that",
                "isn't it",
                "isn't that"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "You had better …………………………. saying thank-you for things.",
            "description": "We use infinitive without to after ‘had better’.",
            "answers": [
                "start",
                "to start",
                "started"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "When we were kids, my uncle ……………………………. us out on his bike all round the countryside.",
            "description": "Would and used to can both be used to talk about habitual behaviour in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "would take",
                "used to take",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "You were foolish to try climbing up there. You ……………………………. yourself.",
            "description": "Could have + past participle can be used to say that something was possible but did not happen.",
            "answers": [
                "can kill",
                "could kill",
                "could have killed"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I am not accustomed to ………………………… personal information to strangers.",
            "description": "After accustomed to we can use an -ing from or an infinitive without much difference of meaning.",
            "answers": [
                "give",
                "giving",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I slowly began ……………………………. what she was going through.",
            "description": "The stative verb understand is usually used in the infinitive form.",
            "answers": [
                "to understand",
                "understanding",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}